MISAEL GALDAMEZ

LOS ANGELES, CA / MIGALDAMEZ@GMAIL.COM

ABOUT

Economic development professional and Master of City Planning graduate from MIT. Experienced in economic research, statistical analysis, and data visualization. Focused on designing novel means of generating inclusive and equitable economic development. Interested in applying an economic development and policy analysis skillset to solve complex planning challenges.

EDUCATION

June 2019

MIT

Master of City Planning

May 2013

AMERICAN UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Arts, International Studies

SKILLS

Adobe Suite R, STATA ArcMap/QGIS Microsoft Office Spanish

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Nov. 2019 -Present

MILKEN INSTITUTE, CENTER FOR REGIONAL ECONOMICS Senior Policy Analyst

- Write white papers, policy briefs, and collaborate on larger research outputs related to regional development.
- Research and analyze relevant policy, legislation, and data.
- · Summarize background research and prepare landscape overviews.
- · Build and maintain relationships with relevant stakeholders from business, government, and nonprofit sectors.

July 2019 -Sept. 2019

DIRECTORATE OF SCIENCE, TECHNOLOGY, AND INNOVATION, PRESIDENT'S OFFICE, SIERRA LEONE Innovation Ecosystem and GIS Intern

- Developed strategy to identify innovation start-ups and firms in Sierra Leone.
- Drafted agenda for cross-national learning exchange with Ugandan ST&I officials.
- · Created visualizations for OpenGIS portal using CartoDB and Apache Superset.

Aug. 2017 -Aug. 2019

MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Research Assistant, Professor Ceasar McDowell

- · Launched The Move, a website and podcast and highlighting the challenges of democratic participation.
- · Wrote and created website content on how to re-envision and recreate civic processes.
- Drafted policy brief for city officials on Professor McDowell's civic engagement framework.
- Graduate teaching assistant for "Engaging Communities" practicum, a course focused on the development of a civic engagement strategy around mobility issues for the city of San Pedro García Garza in Mexico.

June 2018 -Aug. 2018

BOSTON PLANNING AND DEVELOPMENT AGENCY

Downtown and Neighborhood Planning Summer Intern

- Co-designed and coordinated two community engagement exercises to discuss how affordable housing and other community benefits are financed and facilitated community conversation on neighborhood character preferences.
- · Drafted graphics and documents for ongoing planning initiative workshops and meetings.
- · Assisted in visualizing planning and zoning concepts for ongoing planning initiative.

Sept. 2013 -July 2017

INTERNATIONAL MONETARY FUND

Division and Project Coordinator

- · Co-authored working paper analyzing demographic and economic trends of first and second generation immigrants.
- · Co-authored working paper analyzing the macroeconomic impact of remittances and migration in Latin America.
- · Maintained demographic projection datasets and designed graphics for department project on population aging.
- · Organized two high-level conferences for Latin American Ministers of Finance and Central Bank Governors.
- · Coordinated two seminars for 2014 Annual Meetings, including budget, speaker, interpretation, and site logistics.

MISAEL GALDAMEZ

LOS ANGELES, CA / MIGALDAMEZ@GMAIL.COM

ABOUT

Economic development professional and Master of City Planning graduate from MIT. Experienced in economic research, statistical analysis, and data visualization. Focused on designing novel means of generating inclusive and equitable economic development. Interested in applying an economic development and policy analysis skillset to solve complex planning challenges.

RESEARCH AND PUBLICATIONS

INTERNATIONAL MONETARY FUND

- "Different but Equal? An Empirical Analysis of U.S. Immigrants," with Joyce Wong. *IMF Working Paper*, Washington, D.C.: International Monetary Fund, forthcoming.
- "Growing Pains: Is Latin America Prepared for Population Aging?," with Lorenzo Figliuoli et. al. *IMF Departmental Paper No. 18/05*, Washington, D.C.: International Monetary Fund, April 5, 2018. https://bit.ly/3aH69uH.
- "Migration and Remittances in Latin America and the Caribbean: Engines of Growth and Macroeconomic Stabilizers?" with Kim Beaton et. al. IMF Working Paper No. 17/144, Washington, D.C.: International Monetary Fund, July 2017. https://bit.ly/2GolDoo.

MILKEN INSTITUTE

"Preparing California for the Future of Work: Creating Equity by Addressing the Access Gap," with Matt Horton et. al. Santa Monica, CA: Milken Institute, January 2020. https://bit.ly/3aEKNOv.

MIT

- "Designing Public Dialogues for Spatial Justice," with Julia Curbera in *Spatial Justice 2.0*, Boston, MA: Design Studio for Social Intervention (March 2020).
- "El Salario es Para Quien Trabaja! A Methodology for Living Wage Estimations in Mexico City." Cambridge, MA: Massachusetts Institute of Technology (2019). https://hdl.handle.net/1721.1/123954.

BLOGS AND OTHER WRITING

"Planners are People Too." MIT's The Move. https://bit.ly/38Dq2Rr.

"Are You Alive Still?" MIT Graduate Admissions Blog, March 2018. https://bit.ly/2GnizKd.

"An Open Letter to Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu." MIT Graduate Admissions Blog, March 2018. https://bit.ly/2Rqw2XX.